A girl with a great following. Every cop in the state was
after her. Everybody else was behind her.
The Sugarland Express is a crime, drama, comedy
film directed by Steven Spielberg.
Married small-time crooks Lou-Jean and Clovis Poplin lose their baby to the
state of Texas and resolve to do whatever it takes to get him back.
Lou-Jean gets Clovis out of jail, and the two steal their son from his
foster home, in addition to taking a highway patrolman hostage.
As a massive dragnet starts to pursue them across Texas, the couple become
unlikely folk heroes and even start to bond with the captive policeman.
Lou Jean Poplin, played by Goldie Hawn.
Clovis Poplin, played by William Atherton.
Captain Tanner, played by Ben Johnson.
Slide, played by Michael Sacks.
Mashburn, played by Gregory Walcott.
Jessup, played by Steve Kanaly.
The Sugarland Express is a 1974 American crime drama
film directed by Steven Spielberg.
The film follows a woman (Goldie Hawn) and her husband (William Atherton) as they take a police officer (Michael Sacks)
hostage and flee across Texas while they try to get to their child before he is placed in foster care.
The film was based on true events, some of which occurred in Sugar
Land, Texas, where parts of the film were shot.
Other scenes were filmed in San Antonio, Live Oak,
Floresville, Pleasanton, Converse and Del Rio, Texas.
The Sugarland Express marks the first collaboration between Spielberg and composer
John Williams, who has scored all but five of Spielberg's films since.
Although Williams re-recorded the main theme with Toots Thielemans and the Boston Pops Orchestra for 1991's The Spielberg/Williams
Collaboration, the score was not released as an album until June 15, 2024, coinciding with the film's 50th anniversary.
The film premiered at the New Directors/New Films Festival on March 29, 1974, and was released theatrically
in New York City on March 31, 1974, followed by a year-long worldwide theatrical rollout.
The film was a commercial disappointment but received generally positive reviews from critics,
who praised Hawn's performance, Spielberg's direction and the cinematography.
The film explores themes of prison, police, stadium, kidnapping, hostage.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.